Guide to the Reuben A. Holden Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Reuben A. Holden papers
1968-1994
MS 1802
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
The papers consist of Yale related materials created while Holden was the president of Warren Wilson College.
Holden, Reuben A. (Reuben Andrus), 1918-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Warren Wilson College, 2001. Transferred from the Yale University Archives, 2001.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Records of Reuben A. Holden as Secretary of Yale University (RU 19). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Biographical / Historical
Reuben Andrus Holden (1918-1995) was born in Louisville, Kentucky and graduated in 1940 from Yale College. After serving as an infantry officer in World War II, he went on to receive his M.A., 1948, and Ph.D., 1951, in Education from Yale University. He held the position of Yale University's secretary from 1953 to 1971. He then served as president of Warren Wilson College from 1971 to 1986.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of Yale related materials created while Holden was the president of Warren Wilson College.
Holden, Reuben A. (Reuben Andrus), 1918-; Warren Wilson College; Yale University -- Officals and employees
- Inventory, 1968-1994
  - Biographies and eulogies, 1974-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence [general], 1971-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Campaign for Yale, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 4)
  - Dwight Hall at Yale, 1987-1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Homecoming speech, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Memorabilia, 1977, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Yale Class of 1940, 1975-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Yale in China
    - General correspondence, 1971-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10 - 11)
    - Manual for Trustees, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Yale University Council, 1968-1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Yale news releases, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)